Carolina Power and Light Photograph Collection PHC.68
State Archives of North Carolina
- Fort Caswell, North Carolina, c. 1950s. A man and a woman are seen standing at the entrance to the original Fort Caswell on Oak Island in Brunswick county, NC. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.540; Carolina Power and Light
- Crooked Power Pole c. 1930s. A rough, crooked power pole is seen in a rural area. c. 1930s, PhC.68.1.541; Carolina Power and Light
- Line Construction, Atlantic and Carteret c. 1940s. Series of images depicting line construction in Carteret County, NC. A sound is seen with electric poles being run alongside a bridge, electric poles are seen along a roadway, Core Creek bridge is seen with electric poles running alongside, one view of Arendell Street in Morehead City, NC with the Jefferson Hotel in the background. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.542.1-11; Carolina Power and Light
- Electrical Towers at Swannanoa and Asheville, NC c. 1928., PhC.68.1.543.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Transmission Lines, Buckhorn, Raleigh, NC c. 1909. Transmission lines are seen at Buckhorn, a rural area outside of Raleigh, NC. Unidentified buildings in background. c. 1909, PhC.68.1.544; Carolina Power and Light
- Transmission Lines, Old 6600v Dead Ends on Guy Insulators c.1916. A silhouette of electrical lines intersecting on a pole is seen. Back is captioned, "1916 Old 6600v dead ends on guy insulators." c. 1916, PhC.68.1.545; Carolina Power and Light
- Cable Laying, Wilmington, NC 10-11 March 1955. Carolina Power and Light workers are seen at Wilmington, NC laying cable (electrical line). The workers appear to be laying cable under a body of water, possibly a sound. They are seen wrapping lines with old tires then tugboats are seen pulling the line in the water. 10-11 March 1955, PhC.68.1.546.1-7; Carolina Power and Light
- Cable Laying, Morehead City, NC, 16 November 1953. Carolina Power and Light workers are seen using a cable laying barge and tugboats to lay cable between Atlantic-Beach and Morehead City. 16 November 1953, PhC.68.1.547.1-8; Carolina Power and Light
- Cable Laying, Morehead City, NC, 9-10 December 1954. A scuba diver and another man are seen setting out in a small boat as the scuba diver prepares to work on underwater electrical line near Morehead City. Numerous pictures of the lines are seen on shore. 9-10 December 1954, PhC.68.1.548; Carolina Power and Light
- Firetrucks, Weaverville, NC and Cary, NC c. 1950s. Old and new fire engines from the Cary, NC and Weaverville, NC are seen. Cary firefighters are seen pushing an older Chevrolet engine while a man steers. Older 1920s Weaverville engine is seen next to a newer 1950s model engine. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.549.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Seaboard Air Line Engine c. 1930s. A Seaboard Air Line engine is seen at an unidentified station with a rail worker lubricating a part while looking at camera. c. 1930s, PhC.68.1.550; Carolina Power and Light
- Truck, Town of Robbins. c. 1950s. Two men are seen standing next to a GMC truck belonging to the town of Robbins, NC. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.551; Carolina Power and Light
- Southern Pines, NC School Busses. Two photographs of school buses. A new school bus is seen with dozens of kids in and around the bus while several adults hold a sign that reads, "Thanks to all Friends". Second photograph shows older worn school bus. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.552.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light Bus System, Memorial Auditorium, 1945. A new fleet of Carolina Power and Light City of Raleigh buses are seen in a row in front of Memorial Auditorium. Nine men are seen standing beside one another, two men in center are seen shaking hands. c. 1945, PhC.68.1.553; Carolina Power and Light
- Mule Drawn Streetcar for Parade in Raleigh, NC c. 1942. Various pictures of an 1886 vintage mule drawn Raleigh street car. Passengers of the street car have dressed in late 1800's clothing as they are seen in various places around Raleigh, NC including the corner of Edenton and West streets and the Carolina Power and Light offices. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.554.1-10; Carolina Power and Light
- Smith Creek Ford, 5 August 1907. A horse and carriage with one passenger are seen fording a small stream (Smith creek) 5 August 1907, PhC.68.1.555; Carolina Power and Light
- Wrecked Corbitt Truck, Raleigh, NC, c. 1918. Pictured is an early Corbitt truck that has crashed into presumably the power pole seen next to the front of the mangled automobile. c. 1918, PhC.68.1.556; Carolina Power and Light
- Southern Pines 11KV Substation Wiring Diagram c. 1927. Drawing and diagram of Southern Pines 11KV substation general location plan. Produced by Carolina Power and Light. 17 March 1927; Transferred from NC MOH July 2012., PhC.68.1.addition1; Carolina Power and Light
- Laurinburg, NC, 22KV Substation Wiring Diagram c. 1929. Drawing and diagram of Laurinburg 22KV city substation general wiring diagram. Produced by Carolina Power and Light. 9 January 1928; Transferred from NC MOH July 2012., PhC.68.1.addition2; Carolina Power and Light